Shiyi "Ashley" Yue

(315) 746-9070 | ashley.yue117@gmail.com | SF (open to relocate) | LinkedIn | Portfolio

PROFILE

MS in Business Analytics 23' at UC Davis. A data-driven and goal-oriented analytics professional with a strong competency in Python, SQL, and Tableau. Patient in troubleshooting. Value positions that I can grow with.

Skills: Data Wrangling, Data Visualization, Machine Learning, Hypothesis Testing, Experimental Design, Causal Inference Analysis, EDA, A/B Test, Time Series, Image Classification, Big Data, Business Intelligence

Technologies: MySQL, MS SQL Server, MongoDB, R, SPSS, Tableau, PowerBI, Python (Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Scikit-Learn, SciPy, TensorFlow, PySpark), Advanced Excel, AWS, GCP, HTML

Certificates: Machine Learning Specialization, Tableau Desktop Specialist, SQL(Advanced), AWS Cloud Practitioner

EDUCATION

University of California, Davis

San Francisco, CA

Master of Science, Business Analytics (3.7/4.0)

Expected Jun. 2023

Highlighted Coursework: Machine Learning, Advanced Statistics, Big Data, Data Management, Data Visualization Award: Beta Gamma Sigma Membership (Top 20%)

Southwest University of Political Science and Law

Chongqing, CHN

Bachelor of Economics, Economic Statistics (3.8/4.0)

Sept. 2018 - Jun. 2022

Highlighted Coursework: Statistics, Data Mining, Time Series Analysis, Econometrics, Finance, Accounting

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Fashom Miami, FL

Data Scientist (Practicum Project)

Sept. 2022 - Jun. 2023

A fast-paced e-commerce startup planning to offer B2B API solutions regarding personalized recommendations.

- Enhanced clothing attribute **image classification** algorithm accuracy by 40% by revamping model architecture using transfer learning (ResNetV2-50) within **TensorFlow** and utilizing Data Augmentation.
- Extracted, preprocessed, and visualized 63k+ clothing inventory data from **AWS Workspace**, using SQL and Python (including pandas, numpy, matplotlib, seaborn, and requests)
- Leveraged analytical storytelling to adeptly communicate with technical and non-technical stakeholders.
- Improved team productivity by creating reusable Python functions and fostering knowledge sharing, resulting in streamlined workflows and increased efficiency.

PricewaterhouseCoopers (PwC)

Shenzhen, CHN

Business Analyst Intern

Sept. 2021 – Dec. 2021

- Revealed valuable patterns and insights by leveraging MySQL, Python, and Tableau to extract, process, and visualize 210K + daily user engagement data from the client's website.
- Increased conversion prediction accuracy to 76% by applying **Logistic Regression** in Python to user engagement data, using significant features identified by Lasso Regression and business acumen.
- Achieved an 84% accuracy rate in forecasting weekly conversions by developing an ARIMA model in R
 that utilized user engagement metrics, enabling proactive business planning.

Founder Securities Shenzhen, CHN

Industry Analyst Assistant

Apr. 2021 – Jul. 2021

A well-known industry consulting company in China.

- Revealed trends and seasonal patterns by performing EDA on 327K+ monthly sales records in the FMCG industry using Python and MySQL.
- Identified opportunities and threats for the FMCG industry by conducting a **SWOT** analysis.
- Contributed to 30-page industry reports with data visualization via Excel, summarizing key patterns.

PROJECTS

Customer Repurchase Analysis (Python & R: Random Forest, Decision Tree) | Causal Inference Analysis (Python: Causal Model) | Social Network Analysis (PySpark, SQL) | Image Compression (R: PCA) | Default Prediction (R: Lasso Regression, Cross Validation) | Clinics Check-In Analysis (Tableau) | Web Scraping (Python: BeautifulSoup)